I didn't fully lube up my meta walk yet
if you want to help out oh I'm scared
about this man haha it's recording
already
yeah fuck I'm a video editor we can we
can edit it out you know I trust yeah I
think you edit the first part oh I got a
peer at somewhat yes I saw that you had
to do that out of my little clothes I
see you get a sense right like I care
for you I want you to be around a little
bit more good yeah well proper
censorship is important yeah you know I
own everything I just said so I'll leave
it up to your discretion to do it you
will know I think that this is a funny
little topic to start on because they
think that the reality is that I'm not
willing to do anything that's not fun
mmm and if we're not gonna make this fun
amount right like if it's not gonna be
if virtue is not gonna be fun I'm fuckin
out yeah yeah and I think that's one of
the strong attractors that I have my
affinity for Limburg is this fucking
coinage game it's so fun and that's so
the game I want to play it's so the game
I want to play and there's a yeah just
to check in here as I start I'm like I'm
like nervous and like the best way like
not nervous of like self-consciousness
like nervous of like oh god this might
like explode like a the best kind of
bomb yeah yeah yeah let me let me jump
in and report my situ sounds like
there's two things one is that I wasn't
nervous in the like anxiety sort of way
but more so like there's so much do most
that I feel in you and the thumos gets
activated in me and then it's like it's
kind of dangerous a-and I just want to I
just want to do it out with you too
right I just want to like talk crudely
and not be not be shy about it and just
you know you if anybody resort or like
text exchange were probably going to
jail right
and so I just said like go out of like
indulge in that by the same time now
that I know what's recording it's it's
but it's like we you said to like
there's there's a sensitivity to fun
right it might be fun for us but it
might be the opposite of fun for other
people listen to just two Jews talk that
way and so there's a sensitivity to like
I wanna I wanna especially in broadcast
mode I want to try to sort of be not
just appear but be in a way that's like
invites everyone to be have fun mm-hmm
me too I agree there's an inclusion in
that that I think is really beautiful
and there's like the the nervousness
that I refer to and I actually sat down
early today just so I could my like the
sentiment that I feel is that my
preferred delivery system of the
inspiration that I've been getting from
the stoah and from your journals is
likely snorting or maybe even
intravenous and so I like tried to sit
down today so that I could like maybe
like maybe we could slow it down to like
a whiskey sip you know yeah yeah I love
whiskey I love whiskey yeah slow down
too so that's why I grabbed a beer I
think I need a drink man sumos might
just explode though most tell me through
most what's the most still most is the
sec spiritus it's like a Greek word for
a desire for recognition domination you
know the just a conquer right but you
know being right relationship with to
Moses not allowing it to get out of hand
and it leading you you know you got to
domesticate it to a bit this isn't being
a good stuff but comes in being a man of
reason of prudence and knowingly to
unleash new mos and knowing what you
contain it
mm-hmm okay it's just couple things
two things that I'm most excited about
Limburg that you're cool hey you're
trying to make it cool oh yeah because
this is like the ha this is at the heart
of stealing the culture you can't make
something cool you're fucking there come
on everything that is going to take over
it can't just be rational it can't just
be smart it can't just be logical it has
to be fucking cool man
has to be cool has to be fun that's
totally that's that's where I come in
and the second thing is the embodiment
this is the this is really at the heart
of it and I want to introduce a new
psycho technology that I've come up with
it's called enthusiasm Peter it's called
enthusiasm and it's like Stoke Stoke as
currency is something that I've used for
my entire life I have literally traded
my enthusiasm for everything they have
and so that's what I want to that's what
I want to give to you that's what I want
to give to the stoah that's what I want
to give to the people listening it's
like an enthusiasm and also like this
perspective that holy shit like what a
time to be alive like for the burning
fireball of humanity spaceship that us
meta astronauts get a do spacewalks and
look back at and be like whoa and
hypothetically have a have an influence
like this is incredible exciting what a
what a time to be alive what a position
what a position so there's a there's a
thing that I notice in you and this
could be just observational or like it
doesn't necessarily exist but there's a
difference in Peter who leads at the
stoah which being the Stewart at the
stoah I don't know do we call you
Stewart there yeah I'll go with that
hi I'm Stuart at the stoah hi I'm Stuart
- stoah it's like a different thing than
the journals like the journals is like
this version of Peter that's like
fucking
unhinged and he's like yeah he's he's
lost his mind and in the both in the
best way and so there's some there's
definitely some concepts that you've put
forward that have really super excited
me just like even from a queen inch
thing even just from the from a coinage
thing like the concept of being up for
grabs is like yeah god I fucking love
that I love that concept and I'll just
iterate my interpretation of being up
for grabs as being having a clear enough
mind and a nuanced enough perspective
that you can look out on the landscape
of ideas and
have the desire to be seduced by ideas
and the good ones the best ones the
right ones and further it's like this
it's like this this game of Tantra right
that you actually make love to but never
ejaculate to any idea you never sign on
to any idea wholly like in your
identification it's merely just this
ongoing perpetual snowball effect of
like idea to idea - idea to idea and it
almost ties into this thing you've been
talking about this performative agnostic
you're exposing my metagame my friend
stop it have you ever had a have you
ever had an orgasm without ejaculating
you know how my nightstand is a couple
of Montauk Chia books and I'm not
totally sure to be totally honest I I I
feel like yeah I probably have had
something close to that but I definitely
don't think I've had it as powerful of a
sensory experience as I have with
ejaculation I'm not sure if I had it
myself but I strongly think I've had it
multiple times and it's great it's
better than the obvious ejaculation when
you can kind of contain the ejaculation
and still feel the pleasure if not more
so and that's related to sort of being
up for grabs in a way and I would yes
almost everything you said but I would
add this piece is you mentioned the good
ideas right you even want to be up for
grabs for the bad ideas because being in
my opinion and I could be wrong about
this but being maximally seductive is
being at a nice edge of being seduced
yourself
and I feel like I'm like so horny all
the time and like just like I feel like
I can be seduced at a moment's notice
but then and then that really encourages
me to become even more virtuous than
what I was pretending I was or what I
thought I was because now it's risky
it's dangerous I could fuck things up I
can fuck my marriage up you know I could
I could I can fuck my reputation online
up there's so many things that are at
risk right now and this is why I think
it's so important to have fidelity to
the truth and not try to engineer
something not try engineer your word in
order to get some pursue some goal that
you probably even own just be truthful
for its own sake and see what emerges
you have been guilty of that before
which has come more into my awareness
lately as I get more clarity just in
general truth for truths sake and the
really important distinction that I'm
finding in just truthfulness my best
friend and I we had this realization the
other day that like he said my be
truthful about my thoughts muscle is so
strong my be truthful about my feelings
muscle is relatively weak I think that a
lot of us find ourselves in this
paradigm if we really start paying
attention that what we think is easy to
share what we feel is much harder
especially for men and today I just met
modernist men made a modern men as I've
been talking with a lot of women who are
helping out with the stoah and most of
them are obviously intelligent women and
and they hang on men's spaces they're
always sort of like the one or two women
hanging out in men's spaces and the
social power that they have in these
spaces is crazy because they can hang
out with the guys an intellectual
propositional level and they're probably
more intelligent than most them too but
they have more social-emotional fluency
and so you just see them rap dudes
around their finger and use intellectual
spaces these these women and I do this
is why I start with check-ins all the
time with at the stole a session right
because I really wanna I want people to
fucking feel my words you know it's like
there's these certain intellectuals it's
like every single word sounds oarfish I
say that sounds feels the same
this is this monotone quality to it like
a deadness to it fuck that you know like
I don't want to feel dead I want to feel
alive but at the same time I don't want
to compromise intellectual integrity I
want to UM if anyone actually reads my
journals I guard my premise very very
carefully if I maybe needs to be there
and maybe we'll be there and if I don't
guard my premise carefully I'm happy to
be disabused of the the proposition that
I put forth so so bulky but yeah I think
you can have both and I think that is
the sweet spot how both yeah I think one
of the coolest things that I'm taking
away from the verbage that you're
putting to this time is like the liminal
space and the I feel myself like you've
almost described it as losing your mind
and I feel like I'm kind of losing my
mind too like I am beginning to see all
of the ways that I thought I was sure in
the past and now it doesn't make me not
know anything it just turns all of my
thoughts into exactly that it just turns
my enquiries back into inquiries it's
like and it's like it's so good and my
girlfriend is like kind of having some
angst and her work and her Dharma and
yesterday I just invited her to not know
anything and like she was just so
relieved by that
[Music]
it just sounds like you're being a good
philosophy right now - right because
who's the you know the the G the og of
philosophy Socrates the only thing he
knew is that he knew nothing right and
it's like when you know nothing you just
start asking questions after questions
after questions if you're truthful with
it
yo truthful with you you're usually it's
feeling like you're going and saying not
actually going and saying but you're
truthful with that feeling you call it
out then you can process with it
especially if you have loving people
around that's really really important to
have people who not only love you but
are happy to call you on your bullshit -
right but in a loving way and not in the
egoic way like haha you're wrong I'm
right tuck away yes you don't you don't
to be around people like that this is it
this is it the other day I connected
with your friend Daniel Oh got a medical
I'm just hearing that dude that guy is
something dude he is something and
honestly he has so many thoughts and to
be totally honest I didn't hear many of
them because I feel like in my life
right now
if someone is willing to hold that kind
of presence I'm not gonna waste that and
he yeah he has a real real presence to
him totally totally and what we talked
about is this idea that I have that I
want to reinvent manhood that I want to
like put a new facade on philosophy and
on virtue and that's why I think it's
like there's like this two-part idea
that I keep noodling on that's like
making it cool and embodying it and
that's like
cycle the idea of being virtuous is
something that I actually heard eight
years ago but stefan molyneux which is a
drum that he bangs on just over and over
and over and over and I don't see as
much conversation like I guess the
mainstream conversation around virtue is
based in signaling for as far as I can
tell yeah as far as I can tell it is
merely giving a very shallow fuck about
very specific issues and a very shallow
fuck at that like it's not a fuck that
leads you to take action
it's a fuck that leaves you leads you to
repost a meme or to some kind of
call-out culture it doesn't actually
lead you to take a really hard look at
your diet what industries you're putting
money towards what kind of communication
you have with your partner what kind of
virtues you're holding your friends to
what kinds of conversations are having
what kinds of practices you have in your
everyday life and so the thing I was
like noodley knowing with Daniel and
going back and forth was like the idea
of friendship just at large this reality
that you come to to the Epiphany that we
are only relationally existing we
actually don't exist on our own and
everything in our existence is
relationship so I love the bean and
write love relationship to reality I
love this concept I think that
viewing things through the lens of
relation is very poignant right now I
found philosophy like eight nine years
ago I found a peaceful parenting
presentation by Molyneux on YouTube and
at the
time I was and still am mired and
digesting my own adolescence and the
idea of being able to recognize the
moral failings of your parents so that
you can grow out of them so that you can
break the chain so that you can grow up
in a more a truer sense of maturation
led me to like think it's really cool to
be virtuous and it's so rare though it's
so rare to be able to like talk about it
in those terms really um and I found
myself wanting to encourage my friends
to be virtuous and I recorded a podcast
almost two years ago called make your
own mark where you would be up for grabs
in the landscape of ideas you would pick
the ideas that you want to hold yourself
to and you would verbalize those to the
people that you want to be accountable
to for those things that was like almost
and that was like my my shot at
redefining friendship like what how do I
want to be held accountable who do I
want to be and how can I verbalize that
kind of contract so that it's me in
charge of it not my culture not my
parents but it's me that's in charge of
who I become and what standard I'm held
to making your own mark and then of
course it hinges on finding people who
are actually capable of interpreting
that language as well as observing your
behavior through the lens that would
lead them to guide you in a loving
compassionate and effective way back
towards you being in right relationship
and so last weekend I had this super
cathartic huge acid trip that i as i
started to trip out I could feel because
in front of me the party was my best
friend's birthday and my best friend
Matt is like the closest Brotherhood I
think I've ever had in my life
like I taught him to paraglide and
we've built things together and we just
like live two blocks from each other
we're constant communication and I can
feel like palpably like our connection
like our Brotherhood and as I start to
trip out I can feel through ideals
essentially I can feel your connection
and and to Daniel and to these other
people right like that then through
virtue you are finding other people
you're building your tribe through ideal
through virtue through honesty and trust
and like those are the things that bind
me to my friends and so I can feel a
distant connection and it's like a very
powerful beautiful realization that we
can unify through ideals that it it
shows the power of what we're doing of
communicating these these conversations
like this it has a deeper power than
just sitting here and eating out totally
mentally so much there so the word
virtue first of all you mentioned
Molyneux I don't know much what Molyneux
or his definition of virtue even though
he lives in the same city as me they
both live in a city outside of Toronto
which is interesting I never met him and
people who use virtue like Molyneux
there's like a felt sense I like a
reactionary feel to it it's antiquated
concept like was this like you know this
far-right guy whatever and and I know AJ
bond and some of my people who are more
progressive or social justice leaning
they don't like that me when I use that
word because it they they just
associated with this reactionary feel
and then there's the sense that you use
about virtue signaling about showing how
much of a good person you are and the
social justice activists we're doing
this like or people the woke thing but I
would say every mimetic tribe has their
own sense of virtue signaling the way I
view virtue is quite boring and this is
very stoic like just the it's just the
there's the cardinal virtues right the
Stoics and the christians they follow
the cardinal virtues you know prudence
courage temperance justice and actually
the slot ladder three
courage temperance and justice they all
are baked in the first one prudence
prudence is the mother of all virtue and
what is prudence practical reason like I
would like you know you can kind of have
a stronger claim juror or whatnot but
it's is being a person who listens to
reason not only your your own but other
people right you don't allow fumo to
just like steamroll you over or you
don't allow the multi-headed Hydra the
appetites to to rule you most people
most people in this society you know
sadly they're ruled by their appetites
but if you can listen and be in right
relationship with kruseman's reason then
that's virtuous in a way right and
there's all these kind of like kind of
heuristics that come from that like
focus on what's in your control you know
be truthful more fat they love your fate
right all these kind of lived heuristics
that reasoned and experienced heuristics
that form from that yeah that's my I can
keep of it if if you want to jump in I I
feel like what your that even just the
term heuristic is so helpful here
because this is like a foundational
education of the landscape of morality
that know that children are taught as
they grow up right like it is
authoritarian yes or no binary good or
bad punishment or reward that people
grow up bouncing off of there's not
these heuristics like this is the baby
that is thrown out with the bathwater of
religion yeah yeah like well the
cardinal virtues oh my god like
that it has to be a heuristic in
people's minds like you have to be able
to to at least take your own thoughts
and behaviors and measure them up to
like some basic heuristic totally and
when I say your recent heuristics it's
like like the Stoics the Romans the
Greeks they were talking about these
these things focus on what you're in
your control and then modern you know
popular psychology social psychology you
know they're talking about this positive
psychology has gone looking where
they're talking about these things it's
exactly the same that the stores are
talking about but now they have research
behind it so it's not like a like
surprise secret it's out there and
people are earnestly there's there's
there's great people there they're
trying to teach this stuff to people
this positive psychology but in you know
this late the stages of like capitalism
it's like people want you to be addicted
you know they they want you to be slaves
to your appetites because teaching
that's where the money is so they have
no desire for you to be virtuous but
they want you to avert your signal
because they can you know they can co-op
that they can use that to make a buck
that's not real virtue I just want it I
want it I want you to go back and
delineate who they are they that don't
want you to be virtuous versus they who
do genuinely want you to be virtuous so
I think there's people out there that
recognize even though they're probably
flawed like myself that they recognize
that virtue is is is great and you know
it's it's good to be virtuous and so
whatever lens whatever tradition
Buddhism stoicism positive psychology
they're teaching these things that at
least gesture towards that and when I
meant like people who don't want you to
be virtuous it's no people who wants you
to buy shit you don't need essentially
and all the infrastructure and and I
don't want to like it make it sound like
there's good people marketing apartments
there everyone's wrestling with their
own moral dilemma we're all complicit in
this thing so I don't want like they I
don't want to say that but I think you
know what I mean like anything anyone or
anything that wants you to buy shit you
don't need that's not your best interest
and then he'll give a shit because you
know it gets money but I think that your
wife wants you to be virtuous even if
she didn't have the heuristic of those
cardinal virtues I think that deep down
people
we're like I feel like the five cardinal
virtues say are you saying for the
cardinal virtues in general are a
ancient heuristic of our intuitions as
to what makes us work together the best
[Music]
and and you know circle back on brother
Daniel I've known Daniel for four years
now and he's a good friend he's actually
the only like either stoic in the stola
it's like it's only two of us meeting
him and then everyone else is just you
know like whatever there are like that's
cool but you know that game recognizes
game there and you know we are seduced
by virtue in a way for whatever reason
and I wouldn't like Pat myself on the
back like you first principles I just
stumbled on it
about tell your story like a story about
Brotherhood and loving virtue so I was
this me and my wife are just being
radically truthful to each other we're
telling each other secrets that we
haven't told like you know like moments
cuz I'm be more expressive now with my
desire for other women my sexuality and
it's in it's a beast my friend as you
can miss you
I see no game recognizes game I imagined
as a beast in you as well and I just
been you know it's better to be truthful
about this and constantly and I was
telling her like um I backpacked across
Europe I don't like five years now ago
with a good buddy of mine you would love
this guy Kristoff st. Christoph the
guy's a fuckin wild man and you can
remind me of him as well he has the same
you have the same level of through Moses
in us we got together like fucking call
the cops
it's a and so like um yeah so I went
backpacking across Europe with Christoph
right and then we went for a month and
then I was dating Camilla I've been with
Camille for we have we were married at
that point but we've been dating for
almost 11 years now and so we were
together at that time you know like what
happens in Europe stays in Europe and so
she's always wondering did you hook up
with other women right and so just a
spoiler alert no I didn't right but
there was like almost every day I could
have right and I just basically told her
all that liked it the close calls there
was just like oh just like angelic like
Irish girl there was this a hot italian
girl there's this like was always like a
gym german girl danish like oh my god
there's like there's almost mom's I
could have hooked up made up make up
make out whatever I didn't I stopped
myself and I put myself at sort of the
knife's edge of cheating and each of
those interactions that I loved feeling
sexual energy I loved the flirtatious
energy and I could have done it right
like I know enough game in that sense to
make it happen I stopped myself each
time and then when I was kind of telling
Camila all these close calls and then me
not doing it and I'm like yeah why did I
stop myself
mm-hmm it is because I love Camille I do
love Camille so like Cuban as my wife I
love her so much I deeply love her and I
would never like I just have thought of
her crying or being hurt I hate that
right but was that the reason why I I
was faithful like no that wasn't the
reason the reason why I was faithful
because I loved the principle of being
faithful I never cheated was with my
wife her like hopeless you know I never
cheated on her and never may know what
anyone had ever had like sex with anyway
other women even though I wanted to I
never did it and I'd love the principle
of being a faithful man more even if
it's the wrong principle I love that
principle and then that's when I wrote
that homo social kind of love letter
we're just like you know I I love virtue
more than I can love any woman but is
true and Daniel is the same way right
and it's like and I'm imagine you and
your buddy have that something like that
as well this beautiful thing Peter I
love you so much so glad you're alive
so glad you're alive oh I love the
sensitive spiritual height man so funny
so funny that you coined me that I think
you self that I don't think I could do
that
hype man for sure
I just put the word spiritual to it to
me a sexier yeah well I couldn't say
this too about like making virtue sexy
and a lot of like these these people
that I previously threw shade at in our
last conversation these LARPing Stoics
right it would if I have anything stolen
from swords I love this image it's good
so these these larger Stoics who like
they would like if they heard making
virtue sexy look oh you can't do that
you can't do that virtues not sexy your
bastardizing it or whatever right you're
you're being a marketer no that's his
own virtue sickening right there you
know saying so it hurts you cannot be
sexy because like you said it's like
it's like the minimal viable sexiness if
you will right you just need just a
little bit of interest to bring people
in I start like as a Trojan horse and
then you show them that you're you could
be sober as fuck right then you can then
you show them that you're grounded in
actual virtue and I'm not fully grounded
I'm trying you know I'm trying publicly
but there's nothing wrong with having a
little sex appeal because we want to
have sex we want to fuck let's not lie
about it mm-hmm
yeah I think I like what you say the
minimal viable sexiness and I think that
to say that you can't make it sexy is to
completely and totally disregard any
kind of efficacy
I'd like it tries to embody a principle
and I guess this is a inquiry for me
that I would love to jam with you on is
when these heuristics of virtue bring us
to certain epiphanies what is our
responsibility to act on them and this
is both with your sexual appetite and
the commitments that you have
interpersonally as well as your
interaction in the market your
interaction in public the virtue
signaling thing is
slow got it so slow it doesn't change it
doesn't change it people's political has
it one of my hugest epiphanies in this
whole thing was like huh food shortage
possibility yo your political opinions
don't do shit you your fuckin opinions
don't do anything if you are not
embodied you are just dust in the
fucking wind man you're just dust in the
wind and so one of the barometers that I
have of this this phenomenon right now
is a number of my friends who are mired
deeply in conspiracy but it seems to
merely disempower them it just
disempowers them
it just takes all of their fucking power
away and I noticed this in the beginning
here when I started just cranking on the
podcast I was like there's these ideas
that I'm very partial to looking into I
think that the government is abhorrent
and yada yada but
the thoughts of conspiracy theories took
the wind out of my sails but the
conversations with people who are like
actually trying to do something we're
just like fucking set me on fire set me
on fire Peter and so it's like you know
I feel like you know I'm one of the
particular things about my friends who
are conspiracy theorists is they still
go to the grocery store and they buy
factory-farmed beef which I grew up on
an Angus ranch and so I just like have a
little bit of insight and I think that
it's very unlikely that anyone has it he
wanted this day and age hasn't seen some
kind of imagery of factory farming and I
just that's just like a particular stick
that I have and so I am on one level I'm
curious about your diet like literally
what you eat and what you support with
your money that goes into your mouth and
on a broader perspective what is our
responsibility because I like I am so
inspired by the story that you just told
that you're like I love women
I'm does I have so much desire for women
and I have hurt you and I love the
fucking virtue more than I love the
women it's like do you love the virtue
more than you love the steak like how
far does that go where do you know it's
such a rabbit hole and it's so it's such
a fucking Mandelbrot you just zoom in
and you keep zooming and you keep
zooming in there's just new epiphanies
to be had and new behaviors to modify it
seems to me right Ken lubbers idea of
not being spiritually greedy comes to
mind maybe we can swap out the word
spear so with virtuous don't be greedy
with virtue or don't try to be too
virtuous too quickly
and yeah like there's a meta crisis
happening and there's all these
existential risks and there's evil in
the world there's a lot of fucked up
things
environment you know the animal issues
the prison situation so much stuff going
on there's so much stuff we could be
better or more virtuous I'm not that
intelligent I'm not that knowledgeable
ah but I know when people are trying to
manipulate me to do things and sometimes
people are trying to manipulate me to do
things when it's actually a good thing
to do for myself and for the world hard
to tell a difference when you're not
that intelligent I mean you're not that
knowledgeable but I'm intelligent and
not maybe I clever enough maybe that's
better to know that I can't figure all
this shit myself and I need to be in a
community of people who are striving for
virtue and so we can get into it Vicky
calls dial logos so you can figure out
the nitty-gritty of this stuff together
and it's like put the spiritual Akasha
getting masks on right like okay first I
gotta have like a minimal Viable
sovereignty or virtue myself so people
are not just manipulating me here and
there right and then once I got that
then you know build a relationship with
the Dame on your game on get some
intimacy there so no one could separate
the two of you and then and then explore
all these topics
you know like Raven just reached out to
me she says hey what do you think of the
homeless situation of the prison
situation right I'm like I care about
that you know I'm concerned about that
let's bring someone in at the store to
talk about it you know I want I want
feminists could pay feminists to come in
I want people to talk about masculinity
reinventing masculinity or finding it
again these are all important issues
every issues important and not every
issues important but like you know what
I mean there's like so much fucking
there's a wealth of important issues out
there we're to begin you know and why
have a burden on yourself that like you
got to be perfect that seems like it's
coming from an eagle place or it's a
wrong chess move or you're trying to be
too perfect you know forget that you
know start right here right now what's
the most what's the what's the best word
come on my mouth what's the most
virtuous thing I can do knowing that
you're not virtuous right now mm-hmm
I guess anecdotally for me it's just
like there are certain epiphanies that
burden me with decisions like you go to
the grocery store and you know some of
the or you can even imagine just the
back end of what has happened to create
the product that you are about to
support or not support and it's like
going through a modern supermarket right
now is fucking difficult for me
I mean there's so many decisions and
what you're saying is so true that it is
and the imagery of a Mandelbrot keeps
coming a familiar with the Mandelbrot no
a Mandelbrot is is a mathematical
visualization that more accurately
represents nature it is like the
fractals that you can just zoom into and
zoom in and zoom in and it's just
intricacy on intricacy and complexity on
complexity on complexity it never ends
and it's a mathematical equation based
on iterations and it just represents the
reality that just the fucking rabbit
hole never ends and the the I think that
Ken Wilbur's philosophy like integral
philosophy from what I can tell is like
really one of the foundations that I'm
working on and it seems from where I sit
like one of the most important things in
our time right now like Omni
consideration Omni wind yeah a
win-win-win-win-win
like but that realization alone then
makes the grocery store a difficult
place to be it it opens up your
it makes me take on extra cognitive
bandwidth right and I do I proxy that
out to people like Daniel smacking
burger my girlfriend is close friends
with Hin Daniel and two years ago we
started dating and she was like oh you
like philosophy here have you ever heard
a Ken Wilber I was like no who's that
and she was like here here's my friend
Dan or smacking burger and just like my
my my mind exploded and my life changed
like straight out like to think of like
last night I had to apologize to Alisha
because I recognized the ways in which
my old philosophy was still binding her
she was still self-conscious about being
judged by me for through my old
philosophy
Danish Martin burger is absolutely a
huge proxy for me a huge proxy for me
and listening to a 90 minute talk that
he explains his thoughts on veganism is
like pretty robust right also I come
like I grew up on a Black Angus ranch
right like I have washed cows by hand a
hundred days in a row that we have then
eaten right like I know what I can
imagine what a good sustainable
beautiful life of an animal is and I can
certainly consider consuming that and I
don't I I don't actually want to be a
vegan
I want permaculture polyculture where
are these you know it's just cool and it
seems like um that's where you're called
in a way to explore or love food I love
to cook man I love food and I love to
cook
yeah and I'm what ever desire to learn
from you in that area because like I
know and there's a felt sense it's not
that strong but I know like yeah I got
that shit handled sooner or later and
there's sort of a guilt coming online
like I like that I said basically my
wife does makes all the food is she this
is I don't know she orders something
seems organic enough and then they've
had like one meal a day and I'm cookie
slut now eat cookies so that's that's
kind of drink beer so that's basically
my diet uh-huh I don't put much thought
into it my thoughts elsewhere but it's
like yeah not now that you're talking
about this I want someone talked about
this the store I want to address this
issue do some sense making around it as
a collective and I'm I appreciate and
I'm grateful that you're really drawn to
it and you have two most behind it
because you need people to have thumos
become activated when they think about
that issue and how fucked up it is
mm-hmm
yeah I agree and just to share my
girlfriend is an Ayurvedic practitioner
are you familiar with Ayurveda no
Ayurveda as a sister science of yoga was
developed in the Indian subcontinent
like five thousand years ago and it's
one of the first systems of science ever
and Ayurveda
Fink's is like it's whoa it's the og
integral man it is the OG integral it is
literally every single thing is
connected your thoughts and your body
your emotions and your digestion
everything is connected everything is
connected and when you have an ailment
there is both an emotional explanation
for it there is an acute explanation for
it there's a pathological explanation
for it and to treat anything you can't
treat one thing you have to treat
environment you have to treat emotions
you have to treat thoughts you have to
treat practice you have to treat diet
you have to treat exercise all of these
things yoga as we know it is basically
one of eight arms of yoga that's asana
which is doing the physical postures
that's like the physical connection but
yoga as in a general sense is becoming
one with God which is to become in right
relationship with reality
it is absolutely that it is why when we
talk about that I have my finger on the
right relationship with reality that
term is as close as I can fucking come
to like the bullseye right now like as
far as I can tell that's pretty much the
bullseye
for what I need to be doing and for what
I think other people need to be doing
but Ayurveda has a very interesting way
of thinking about diet and I'm vastly
under educated in this so I'm gonna give
an overview but basically there are
diets that you could have that would
support you in enlightenment and this is
a saatvik diet these are things that are
not heating these are you don't eat
onions
you don't eat garlic you don't need
peppers you definitely don't eat any
animal products and these are diets that
allow you to sit in meditation that are
calming for your mind and as Alicia came
into my life two and a half years ago I
before Alicia I was married to a Mexican
woman for a decade I've been to Mexico
25 times I had
I can cook anything Mexican I can cook
all kinds of salsas all kinds of shit
and I can eat Ari I could eat really
spicy food at the time and she never she
never told me how to change my diet but
she did lead by example I said why do
you eat like that she says oh it's
calming for my mind
and so as our combined kitchen as we
began to cohabitate our grocery list
just kind of integrated and the things
that I only ate just kind of fell out at
the onions the garlic the peppers and I
noticed like I was like holy shit like
it doesn't upset my stomach it doesn't
upset my brain and I literally felt a
connection between the thoughts in my
head and the food in my stomach and so
from an integral perspective I don't
know if you've read integral life
practice that's I did I did yeah it's so
good man it's so fucking good it's just
like it just kind of puts some dots on
the side of this like space tube that
we're going through that's like this is
what an integral perspective might
possibly look like if you're talking
about what you should eat or what you
should do or what time you should wake
up or like anything and it's like and
fuck my interview of Terry Patton was
just like life-changing I'll fucking
love that guy I love that guy he loves
me this is I think that what you said
about like the proxy that Peters head is
full of myriad things and my head is
full of myriad things man and like there
are some things that have been in my
head long enough that when you build up
enough trust with me that you can just
proxy out to me hmm
right and that's an inch
steam point in friendship in trust in
sense making this like relates to the
sense making conversation of how it
important it is to have like a
high-bandwidth relationship that you can
actually proxy out things to people as
well as the personal burden of your
relationship to virtue because like I
said in initially like making your own
mark like if Peter tells if you tell me
that I shouldn't do something that I
don't currently prioritize as important
the chance that I do it is very low but
like by making my own mark and by
elevating my sense making that I
realized that my decisions are very
impactful for my own life my friends
life my partner's life the fucking my
community the world cosmos this whole
thing right it's like it the backpack
gets heavier the backpack gets heavier
and I think that one of the most
foundational things that Peterson just
fucked in the drum that Peterson bangs
on is like your backpack should be
heavier your backpack should be heavier
you should have more responsibility you
should be able to consider more people's
impact of your own thoughts your own
words your own behavior totally I'm a
fucking Jordan Peterson fanatic I love
that guy and I haven't yet killed him as
my intellectual father I don't know if I
told you this I don't know I don't know
if Daniel told this to you too but
Jordan Peterson introduced me and Daniel
together really yeah because we were
both his client he was my therapist for
two years was dating a service for a
year or so and then I was running a
mastermind group all men's master friend
we've actually and then Daniel was like
dealing with a crazy that kind of like
procrastination issues and stuff and
then so Peterson sent him to me and then
we became like mastermind he joined my
mastermind group essentially
that's how we met so yeah we have we
have the Peterson connection
as well and I love Peterson I don't
agree with him in every area and I have
sort of um I would push back on his
approach to an extent but at the same
time I wouldn't because that's just
we've come out of ego and he's been
through fucking hell recent lately yeah
yeah yeah and then you know I just I
just want to shine love with his way me
too man that's what I that's what I I
feel that too I don't need to
I mean I'm sure there's things I
disagree with him on but like man I
really his sense making is really super
high up on my list and I have just such
gratitude for the light I have gratitude
for Molyneux for smocked and burger for
hall for all these people that that I
like can feel into their since making
deep enough that it like literally
changes my life it changes my mind oh
and I have just such a fuckin gratitude
for these kind of people and I have a
gratitude for you for the influence that
you have on me too Peter mmm-hmm feels
good hearing that and one thing I'll say
something about Peterson that want to
jump back to something said like one
thing about Peterson it's like he
doesn't speak a dead language
you know his words are alive you feel
them you don't like the song I have I
have a trouble I have trouble like
concentrating on some of these galaxies
brains when they talk because you don't
feel their heart there's every words
feel the same I just don't know and or
if I have to really kind of like put on
my hat on to focus my focus hat right
the Peterson I never have to like put on
my focus that I'm just like uh he's like
he's alive he fused himself with the day
one totally and yeah something else came
alive there when you were talking oh
yeah it slipped my mind
tell me about the daemon I mean I like
and and there is such context in your
writing that I never have to look
anything up I know what I know what you
mean but I want to hear it from you like
I want to hear the Peter definition of
the day a month didn't we talk about
this last conversation okay I think I
talked about so much time like I'm like
talk about this fucking game one thing
again and yeah it's just like I'll talk
about it in an innocent way in a secular
lens too it's like um just a certain
quality of intuition that feels really
right that dare I say feels delicious
and it doesn't provide any guarantees if
you listen to it and if you follow it
but it very confidently points in a
certain direction mm-hmm and it's not
shy about pointing that direction and
that direction might be scary it might
be uncertain but if you follow it
whether it's good or bad it's going to
be an adventure so whatever that
intuition is that's what I dubbed the
daemon and then there's a historical you
know like Socrates said he he just
followed his Dame on you know and he the
only thing he knew he knew nothing and
if you know nothing what do you do how
do you guide yourself my first principle
reasoning
you know just hand your keys over the
fucking Dame on and see where it takes
you and try to be truthful while you're
doing it and then being truthful front
of others that's basically how I got my
life right now in the last two months
especially so there's no sort of sort of
secret there and then one thing that
came online the quote came to mind I
mentioned it's what my journal but keep
the mind before I was gonna jump on with
you so I'll mention it is that a de
Chardin the guy who claimed the
noosphere said this he said that we're
not human beings having a spiritual
experience we are spiritual beings
having a human experience right and so
it's really kind of like trippy thought
experiment to flip you know my Peter
just having access to the Dame one or
his Dame one the Dame one having access
to Peter and then she'd become really
identify with the Dame one is really
feeling that felt sense and just
anthropomorphize it and be it and then
it's like wow like this you're just kind
of fun he's funny he's like this fucking
crew he's horny all the time you know
like he wants to make fart jokes didn't
get serious like he's hungry
you know like it's like he wants to lick
his wife every inch every that's like
it's like like that's like so human
right and I have all this blue-collar
desires here there's so human and then
when you look at it from that spiritual
lens is that spiritual being it's kind
of like this is kind of fun you can
appreciate it and not this not judge it
too so I I would I would push back that
they shared and I don't I don't think
we're just spiritual beings I also think
we're human beings too like this have
that postmodern skill set kind of flip
back and forth both in yeah I wanna send
you love and appreciation your way to
men I just really enjoy you and just
like the first conversation thank you
guys I didn't want to do any podcast at
all and I'll fuck you know and I just
called it out like like I don't wanna be
here I could tell you that kind of annoy
like fuck is this guy
legit and then then we have fucking
amazing conversation I think I wash it
like twice and it sounds so fun I posted
on my channel and I hope the post is one
on my channel and yeah there's like a
this guy's a brother you know it's like
I feel kinship with you already
I appreciate your immune you're my life
I love your spiritual hike madness
wherever that is about you I want to be
your spiritual height man
you know I just wanna fucking let's just
heal and introduce this culture man it's
win this liminal Wars fucking get it you
know yeah you know this I appreciate
that Peter and the I actually on our
first conversation when you were like I
don't really want to be here it was
almost like I actually kind of liked it
I can it was like almost a challenge it
was almost a challenge and I was like
yeah you just don't know what you're
looking for you don't know it's about to
blow up you don't know it
then like eight minutes later you're
like this is fuckin sweet dude I had a
couple of actually people reached out
and just reflected on that dynamic which
I really appreciate just the
truthfulness is like something that I'm
just that's one of the things that I'm
kind of looking up to you and I'm like
as I just practice it on a basic level I
just see how even though I was truthful
with my feelings there was like a game
theoretical motivation it wasn't always
earnest even in the last like six months
even with my partner I'm just like eff
like as we've gone through this last two
months thing together I've like had to
apologize on a number of occasions I'm
like I think that I was like there was
some game theoretical shit going on and
I'm still trying to cleanse that and
still trying to repent and that's some
tension with Daniel and I too and the
way I look at it is if Steven loses a
three phases of power yeah I mean only
because you've talked about it the other
day with David fuller yeah that's enough
that's why it's coming online right it's
like there's like the content level what
they call a decision making level
there's the a non decision-making level
agenda-setting level or the frame and
then there's the ideology level and the
one that people miss is the the middle
one agenda setting is whoever controls
the agenda the frame not only just about
like a meeting right but actually of a
conversation you know like and people
just unconsciously buy into frames if
someone becomes a dick and then like his
ego and it disagrees in a very strong
way he's basically saying oh we're
playing this game right now mm-hmm and
then people just buy into that frame but
okay so I got a disagree right but no
like if you're stoic and you have
awareness of all these levels you can
kind of just step back a little bit like
yeah let's do some medical unit a shin
here and call out why Rafe and having
this conversation so we can make our
intentions symmetrical so they're not
asymmetrical right and sociopaths are
really fucking good at manipulating
these levels they can play at all the
levels and so why not have the same
skill set but use it for good use it for
virtue and then when you're when you
when you flex the strip from this muscle
you can talk to each one of those levels
you can talk to the level of
decision content proposition you can
talk to the level of the metaframe why
we're here the agenda you can talk to
the ideology of what influences the
agenda and if all those are up for grabs
you know if you're up for grabs in all
those areas then some real interesting
things gonna happen then you can yes and
you can improv each one of those areas
together that's true dialogue OHS that's
where true emergence happens I know that
I feel like what you're referring to is
just so like I loved it and at the same
time I'm afraid that we were closer to
fucking Mars than we are to that do you
mean by that like the level of
communication that you're referring to
is so far out of the awareness of the
99.999% of humanity and even as you
describe it I find myself in there that
you're like then I'm like that someone's
a dick and I instantly I'm like you just
like change my frame and I don't even
recognize it in the time being and like
later on I digest the conversation I'm
like oh like I actually don't want to
fight with you at all I don't I don't
want to engage like that whatsoever but
like in the moment it's like yeah it's
different project I got I I'm hijack a
ball still I don't want to be here I'm
hijack a ball still and I don't want to
be like amygdala hijacking right nurse
narcissist a sociopath they know how to
lean on to make amygdala hijack and you
know if we take all the people are the
people that they the marketers the the
you know the architects of the
capitalist society every want
cartoonishly label it like you know a
lot of them are sociopaths
it's like trickle-down ethics they're
you know I mean they just wanna hijack
you and so they and then they control
the that the top level of that power and
they can write what becomes just
absolute conditioning that justifies
their authority right and then if we
want to go to the I don't like using the
word conspiracy anymore like I promised
myself I won't use it because it's to
which egg is with it I like the word
pear
politics it's not my it's a new Peter
Dale Scott I think came up with it and
it's basically the deep politics instead
of public politics and if you kind of
look at you know there's a criminal
underworld and then they have certain
rites of passages certain ways to
control and there's also a criminal
overworld to the mega-rich you know they
had like the freaking ring of guy geez
they can do everything want and what's
the criminal overworld look like that's
when you start finding some signal and
the noise of all this conspiracy theory
stuff and this is when it gets dangerous
so we shouldn't talk about it that's
what I'm saying unless we have another
beer it's that yeah I do think there's
something to explore there you're like
you're like you just walk through like a
very dry grassland of my mind with a
torch on the ground and you're like
let's not talk about it and I'm like put
this out put that out you can't put that
out I just did there's a couple things
that your your interview with David
fuller on the rebel wisdom was so fuckin
good man I don't think so good and
there's a couple of things and you know
today I wanted to introduce that new
psycho technology that I talked to you
about enthusiasm oh yeah yeah and it is
so closely tied to that thing that you
you said we're damned if we do and we're
damned if we don't because there is a
religion of religiosity to the claims
being made about coronavirus we're gonna
use it as an example and to make a
alternative narrative claim with a
similar intensity is labeled as
conspiracy and it's almost like it's
almost like a level of intensity or a
level of enthusiasm gets you that that
sets off the the conspiracy radar
I'm not sure I'm following is it it's
just like if you jump into the noosphere
social media with too much enthusiasm
there's like okay this guy's
uncontrollable he's too weird expiry or
whatever labeled racist if you want to
go that route just so they can kind of
throw you away
is that the idea yeah exactly what you
were saying on the on that interview was
you use the term we're damned if we do
and we're damned if we don't like to
fight the institutional narrative with
another narrative whether it is nuanced
or not with a similar level of intensity
that seems to garner some kind of
religiosity in its premise the idea is
thrown out regardless of the content
mm-hmm and I don't I'm not sure I have a
point here I just this is my reflection
on what really set off a bomb in my mind
of the connection between how believable
a narrative is and its intensity which
is a dimension of argument that I hadn't
actually like tuned into which i think
is really interesting and the trick is
how can he be truthful develop a
truthful narrative with the same level
of intensity and you know that I don't
know if this is true but I think I heard
this that the etymology of the word
enthusiasm is be possessed by a god
right so when you're fully learned and
you know the de Mond is basically God's
messenger that's the destiny the not so
dirty secret if you want to look at it
with that metaphysics and if you fully
fuse yourself with the de menthe
then you know you're Messenger of God or
whatever spiritual metaphysics you want
to use so I really liked enthusiasm
because I I fucking feel enthusiastic
you know I feel you're enthusiastic it's
like you need that enthusiasm to like be
turned on right to to make love with the
world properly and to go up again yeah
yeah it's not just a one-hit wonder here
because shit man I have crashed in every
possible way you can crash on all kinds
of different
objects and it's like you gotta have
some enthusiasm to get back up and dust
yourself off and jump again I understand
and yeah with the parent political stuff
it's this is this is where Alexander
bard I don't know if you know him we
should interview him I think you'd be
good for you guys to mix like watch the
when he came on the stoah and the stoy
channel so I was in depart he's he's a
trickster and he might do a series of
regular series it's still called
trickster ology and you kind of be a
trickster like mean fuller called it
playing chess with canceled culture but
there's like a deeper level like
embraced the archetype of being a
trickster because if we're gonna steal
the culture a thief comes unannounced he
doesn't come in with guns a-blazing all
right so I think you got to be a little
trickster here in order to get something
done and I think you can do it
authentically
and you can talk about how you're doing
too - yes - I still do it and that's the
esta I don't have a problem cuz fuller
wants to be you know what's big he wants
to like make it accessible right now I'm
okay being obscure I'm okay no one
knowing what I'm talking about but some
people do and it's sort of like finding
the others at first and then building
that tribe that Brotherhood that's just
your hood of virtue and then getting
into community cos with each other so it
becomes unbreakable so then the cult
you know cannot do a Mikula hijacks on
us atomized us and then do it are the
fuck they want right the age of boy
Kings are over
I'm just gonna call this so we're at the
Aramark and I have to I have to do a few
things before the next stoah session but
I wanted to say this man if you want to
do a session on this though like like
enthusiasm or being a spiritual height
man we can call that being a spiritual
height man it was just like I don't care
what you do just this talk fill everyone
with do most another thing I wanna say
too is if if you want to MC you can do a
post on your podcast too if it's overlap
but if you want to MC a stove a session
where we talk about kind of the ethical
aspects of diet I would love for you to
find some expert in that area and
interview them in the snow and you can
do a post on your podcast if you like to
so that so - Damon spider ideas just
came up and I wanted to throw them at
you I'm gonna be the emcee at the stoah
for Shayne Ward or something okay do it
dude I mean I think it we could go like
this until I'm blue in the face
realistically I've got lots of things
realistically I have this like funny
visualization where the world is like a
rave that has all different stages and
the government is like this suited guy
with an earpiece and a side arm and very
rigid and the religious guy is wearing a
funny hat and the soft smile and there's
this like kind of like broken down tent
the Peters in front of rubbing his
nipple in a way that's half joking and
totally serious and inside you've got
like Steve Beatty gun so has a group of
people hyperventilating and Tyson is on
stage freestyling and dude Sarah NASA is
a circle of everyone holding hands and
it's like and you're the height man
outside the story and everyone in Peters
everytime my pleasure man another great
conversation I'm glad to come back
another time yeah I really appreciate it
I appreciate your inspiration I
appreciate your truthfulness that's
something I look up to a lot and I'm
working on flexing that muscles and
lifting heavy things and keeping a heavy
backpack on
excellent I can fuckin do my card here
oh he did the one thing I wanted to say
about that thing right it's like Ken
Wilbur's quote came to mind is it hurts
more but it bothers you less right so
yeah it's a burden for sure it hurts
more but it kind of bothers you less
especially we have good people like
yourself around yeah it hurts more to
not cheat on your wife but it bothers
you way less you know I got a hurts
right in that moment you're like yeah
something I could have that I can't that
I'm not going to have especially get
more options you get more options you
more you know it's like all right it's
like yeah you know it hurts but it's
like you know it doesn't really bother
me that much because it's like yeah it's
fun doing whatever I'm doing I love it
fucking Brotherhood and virtue my man
glad to be a part of it
yeah brother Peter thanks mister I love
you too